let questions = [
    {
        id: 01,
        question: 'How many bits make a byte?',
        alternatives: ['16 bits', '8 bits', '24 bits', '12 bits'],
        correct: '8 bits',
        expo: 'A byte is a unit of digital information that consists of 8 bits. Each bit can represent a binary value of either 0 or 1. Therefore, 8 bits make up a byte.',
    },

    {
        id: 02,
        question: 'The first search engine on the internet is',
        alternatives: ['Archie','Google', 'Bing', 'Yahoo'],
        correct: 'Archie',
        expo: 'Archie was created in 1990 by Alan Emtage and allowed users to search for file names on FTP (File Transfer Protocol) servers. It was the precursor to modern search engines like Google, Bing, Yahoo etc.',
    },

    {
        id: 03,
        question: 'The number of bits used by IPv6 address is',
        alternatives: ['16','32','64','128'],
        correct: '128',
        expo: 'IPv6 addresses are 128-bit long, which is significantly larger than the 32-bit length of IPv4 addresses. ',
    },

    {
        id: 04,
        question: 'The first web browser invented in 1990 was',
        alternatives: ['WorldWideWeb','Internet Explorer','Mosaic','Nexus'],
        correct: 'WorldWideWeb',
        expo: 'The WorldWideWeb was the first web browser ever invented in 1990 by Sir Tim Berners-Lee.',
    },

    {
        id: 05,
        question: 'Which technology is used to record cryptocurrency transactions?',
        alternatives: ['Mining','Digital Wallet','Blockchain Technology','Token'],
        correct: 'Blockchain Technology',
        expo: 'Blockchain technology is used to record cryptocurrency transactions. It is a decentralized and distributed ledger technology that securely records and verifies transactions across multiple computers.',
    },

    {
        id: 06,
        question: 'One of the advantages of information technology is',
        alternatives: ['Streamline Communication','Easy to hurdle','Both a and b','None'],
        correct: 'Streamline Communication',
        expo: 'it makes communication more efficient and effective by providing various tools and platforms for instant messaging, video conferencing, and email.',
    },

    {
        id: 07,
        question: 'The first computer virus was known as',
        alternatives: ['Rabbit','Elk cloner','SCA virus','Creeper program'],
        correct: 'Creeper program',
        expo: 'The first computer virus is known as the Creeper program. It was created in the early 1970s and targeted the ARPANET, which was the precursor to the internet. ',
    },

    {
        id: 08,
        question: 'What technology is used to make telephone calls over the Internet possible?',
        alternatives: ['VolP','Bluetooth','Ethernet','All of the above'],
        correct: 'VolP',
        expo: 'VoIP stands for Voice over Internet Protocol, which is a technology used to make telephone calls over the internet.',
    },

    {
        id: 09,
        question: 'What is the full form of (CPU)?',
        alternatives: ['Central Processing unit','Critical Processing unit','Crucial Processing unit','Central Printing unit'],
        correct: 'Central Processing unit',
        expo: 'CPU stands for Central Processing Unit, which is the primary component of a computer system responsible for executing instructions and performing calculations.',
    },

    {
        id: 10,
        question: 'The process of starting or restarting a computer is called: ',
        alternatives: ['Start up point','Booting','Connecting','Resetting'],
        correct: 'Booting',
        expo: 'Booting prepares the computer for use and allows the user to interact with the system.',
    },

]